

ERWIEN TJIPTA WIJAYA

Address: Apartemen OASIS Mitra Sarana

Senen Raya No. 135, Jakarta Pusat

Phone: 081-333-1051-49

Email: erwien.wijaya10@gmail.com
Repositori: https://github.com/erwienwijaya

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/erwien-tjipta-wijaya-79057428/

SUMMARY

I have almost 15 years of experience in the information technology and education industry. I have high motivation to learn new things. Able to communicate well from bottom level to top level (C-Level), can work with teams, have the ability to organize and coordinate with one team and with other teams. I like new challenges outside my job specialization and I like analytical thinking.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Practitioner Lecture, FILKOM Universitas Brawijaya - Malang

Apr 2024 - May 2024

 Provide theoretical and practical training for the utilization of Docker in courses Analisa Desain dan Sistem Informasi

Full Stack Data, The Edge Property Ltd (edgeprop.sg) - Singapore

Dec 2021 - Dec 2022

- SQL service design and optimization so that the process can run quickly and correctly.
- As crontab or service admin using stackstorm.
- Ingestion of data into the data warehouse through web scraping with Python.
- As an AWS EC2 admin to ensure that the data ingestion server can run properly according to the schedule managed on **Stackstorm**.

Data Analyst, PT. Alpha Teknologi Indonesia (alterra.id) - Jakarta

Feb 2020 - May 2021

- Creation of data visualisation reports for C-level requirements.
- Create Business Intelligence Dashboard as Insight Report (Transaction, GMV, Margin, Cohort).
- As admin and developer of a BI Dashboard app built using Flask Python and Tableau.

System Analyst, PT. Alpha Teknologi Indonesia (alterra.id) - Malang

Oct 2019 - Jan 2020

- Analyze business process needs and coordinate with Product Manager and Development Team.
- Conduct business process documentation through diagrams (ERD, DFD, UML and BPMN).
- Monitoring the UAT process until it reaches the end user.

Mentor, Alterra Academy (academy.alterra.id) - Malang

Jun 2018 - Oct2019

- Create a curriculum for boot camp (JavaScript and TypeScripts)
- · Mentoring mentee in class

Software Engineer, PT. Alpha Teknologi Indonesia (alterra.id) - Malang

Jun 2018 - Oct2019

- Create Restfull API which will be used by Mobile Engineer and FrontEnd Engineer.
- Establish a scheduled payment system service.
- Perform endpoint enhancement and optimization of bugs or new features.
- Implement agile methodology with best practice scrum and kanban.

Lecturer of Information Systems, Universitas Merdeka - Malang

May 2017 - Jul 2018

- Conduct teaching, research and community service.
- · Active as coordinator of the Journal of Information Technology and Management.
- · Active as a student mentor in GEMASTIK events.

Lecturer of Informatics Engineering, Institut Asia (STMIK Asia) - Malang

Oct 2009 - Jun 2016

- Conduct teaching, research and community service.
- Former Head of Informatics Engineering Department and Head of LP3M.
- · Active as a student mentor in GEMASTIK events.

Programmer, PT. Infoglobal Autoptima (infoglobal.co.id) - Surabaya

Feb 2005 - Mar 2007

- Creating a desktop app for the payment system at PT PLN (Persero).
- Creating a GIS app for substation or feeder information at PT. PLN (Persero).
- · Monitoring and fixing bug lines of code.

Head of IT, PT. Delta Mitra System - Surabaya

Ags 2003 - Jan 2005

- Coordination with development team and Product manager.
- Reporting budget, needs and development progress to C-Level.
- Perform code review, code merging with tortoise svn.
- Designing development budgeting needs.

Programmer, PT. Indoplastika Jaya Abadi - Sidoarjo

Mar 2002 - May 2003

Apr 1998 - Oct 2003

- Creating a desktop-based ERP app.
- Monitoring and fixing line of code bugs.
- Technology migration by revamping from VB 6 to VB .Net.

EDUCATION

Master Of Computer Apr 2006 - Nov 2011

Institut Sains dan Teknologi Terpadu Surabaya (ISTTS), Surabaya

· Information Technology Study Program.

Bachelor Of Engineer

Institut Teknologi Adhi Tama Surabaya (ITATS)), Surabaya

Informatics Engineering Study Program.

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- Technical Skills: Python, PHP, Nodejs, Laravel, Django, Flask, Tableau, SQL, Docker dan GIT.
- · Languages: English and bahasa
- Awards/Activities: Alterra Public Speaking, 5 Days MBA Workshop, Data Science (DQLab), Tableau (Udemy), Crash Course on Python (Google), Praktisi Mengajar Flagship Universitas Brawijaya